{
    "id": "fbb35cec08d84bac8ff00c0a8f3ce74c",
    "title": "Conjunctions Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "I didn't go to the party .................... I was feeling a bit tired.",
            "description": "The conjunction because indicates the reason for something. ",
            "answers": [
                "because",
                "however",
                "although",
                "so"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you know the reason ...................... she is angry with me?",
            "description": "After reason we use that or why. Because is not used after why.",
            "answers": [
                "why",
                "because",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She had ...................... many children that she didn't know what to do.",
            "description": "So...that is a conjunction. Too and very cannot be followed by that-clauses. ",
            "answers": [
                "too",
                "so",
                "very"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "We send them weekly reports ........................... they may have all the information they need.",
            "description": "The conjunctions so that and in order that are used to talk about purpose. So that is more common in an informal style. ",
            "answers": [
                "so that",
                "in order that",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "Send the parcel express ...................... they get it before Monday.",
            "description": "We use so that to indicate purpose.",
            "answers": [
                "so that",
                "so as to",
                "in order to",
                "provided that"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Do you know a shop ................. they sell used cameras?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "there",
                "where",
                "wherever"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "You may borrow my car ........................ you drive carefully.",
            "description": "All of these conjunctions are used to state conditions. ",
            "answers": [
                "as long as",
                "so long as",
                "provided that",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "........................ we go by bus or train, it will take at least 3 hours.",
            "description": "We can use whether ... or as a double conjunction. Its meaning is similar to 'it doesn't matter whether...or'.\r\n",
            "answers": [
                "Whether",
                "If",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "Why is he looking at me ......................... he knew me?",
            "description": "The conjunctions as if and as though mean the same. ",
            "answers": [
                "as if",
                "as though",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "..................... some people insist that smoking should be banned, others disagree with that view.",
            "description": "We use while to connect two contrasting ideas. ",
            "answers": [
                "While",
                "When",
                "As"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I am going out ....................... I have brushed my hair.",
            "description": "We use as soon as to suggest the idea that one event happens immediately after another.",
            "answers": [
                "as far as",
                "as soon as",
                "as long as"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "No sooner had I closed my eyes, ................... the telephone rang.",
            "description": "Sooner is a comparative word. It is followed by than. ",
            "answers": [
                "when",
                "before",
                "than"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}